Now, let's go look at our slideshow for
a little bit. And I want you to pay
attention to where the green arrow is.
So, it starts here and we do some
processing and then it moves over one.
And we do some processing and it moves
over one. And we do some processing and
it moves over one. We do some more
processing and it moves over one. Do
some more processing.
And you'll notice it stopped almost at
the end of the array. So we will know
we've written. So you'll notice it
repeated the arrow just slowly moved
down. When you see something slowly
moving through logic, I want you to
think of a loop because we started at
one and went up to five. If you want to
start at one and go up to five, that's
very, very doable with a for loop. So we
will know our code will work if we can
write a for loop that moves an arrow
from 1 to 5. So from the beginning of
our array to almost the end of our
array. So let's just go try and log
those numbers. So we'll come over here
to Visual Studio Code. We're only
worried about the arrow portion. We're
not worried about any swapping. We'll
get there in a minute. We just want an
arrow that will print out where it's at.
And we don't want it to go quite to the
end of the array. So let's write that.
So we'll say for
let um counter equal well we know we
want to start at the beginning of the
array zero because that's where our
arrow started.
Then we'll put a semicolon. And then
we'll say let's set how long do we want
to run? Well, we want to run 0 1 2 3 4.
We don't actually want to include the
fifth one. So we just want to run
through the first um zero through four
positions. Or in other words, if this
length, if this array has six positions
and we want to go 0 through four, then
we want to run just less than five
times. Or in other words, we want to run
just less than the length of the array
minus one. So we'll say our counter is
less than numbers.length.
So that would be six. And then we'll
subtract off one, which will be 5 minus
1. So it will run 0 1 2 3 4 because our
array is length 6. 6 - 1 is 5 and we're
running less than it. So it'll be 0 1 2
3 4. We will know this works
if we can print out the numbers 4 5 6 1
and 2. So we'll put a semicolon here and
then we'll say counter plus bus plus bus
plus bus plus bus plus bus plus bus plus
bus plus bus plus bus plus bus plus and
we'll do open curly braces close curly
braces and what we'll do is we'll log
numbers array at the counter position.
So we'll save it and we'll come over to
sorry come over to our running code
we'll reload the page and we get um four
five six one two three. Let me go check
that I saved my code cuz I never
remember to do that. Oh, I forgot to log
it. Okay, right here we're going to log
this console.log numbers at the counter
position.
So, we'll save that
and we'll come over here. We'll reload
our page. We'll look at our console and
we get 45 612
which was what we were hoping we would
get. We were hoping we'd get four 5 6 1
and 2 because we are now able to have an
arrow that goes over each of those four
numbers.
So now we know that this code is
successfully working. So, we're going to
comment it out and leave it for